A Finding Aid to the Henry Varnum Poor Papers, 1873-2001, bulk 1904-1970, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Photographs, 1893-1984; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 2.3 Linear feet Boxes 7-8, 12-13
  - People, circa 1893-1967; 9.3; Archival Resource Key
    - Henry Varnum Poor with Family, Archival Resource Key
      - Family Groups (with Bessie Breuer, Marion Dorn, Anne Poor, Josephine Lydia Poor, and Peter Poor), 1913-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Family, Archival Resource Key
      - Breuer, Bessie, circa 1940s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 36)
      - Dorn, Marion Victoria, circa 1910s-1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 37)
      - Poor, Anne, circa 1920s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 38)
      - Poor, Candide, circa 1957-circa 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 39)
      - Poor, Josephine Graham, circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 40)
      - Poor, Josephine Lydia, 1951, circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 41)
      - Poor, Peter, 1926-1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 42)
      - Relatives [?], Unidentified, 1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Individuals, Identified, 1912; 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 44)
      Terry Anderson
      Mayfield
      Martha Rhyter
      Rosse children
      Marjorie Content Tooner
    - Individuals, Unidentified, circa 1930-circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 45)
      Man
      Children
    - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, Archival Resource Key
      - Classes and Students, circa 1946-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 46-47)
      - Faculty and Visitors, circa 1946-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Oversized Photographs of Henry Varnum Poor scanned with Box 8, Folders 17-18, 24, 27, 46-47, circa 1926-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 4-7)
  - Places, circa 1906-1943; 9.4; Archival Resource Key
    There are many photographs of Alaska taken in 1943 when Poor was a war correspondent. Landscapes and aerial views of the territory, boats and boatbuilding, dogs, airplanes, buildings, and other subjects illustrate village life. Some illustrations for An Artist Sees Alaska are based on these photographs.
    Photographs of places do not include houses designed and built by Henry Varnum Poor.
    - Alaska, Archival Resource Key
      - Aerial Views, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 49)
      - Airplanes (Ft. Richardson and/or Ft. Ladd?), 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 50)
      - Boats and Boatbuilding, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 51)
      - Buildings, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 52)
      - Dogs, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 53)
      - Landscapes, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 54)
        Oversized material housed in Box 13, Folder 8
      - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 55)
      - People, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 56-58)
    - Various Subjects, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 59)
      Contact sheets
    - California, circa 1906-1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - France (landscape, Institut Militaire), circa 1911-1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Kansas (Poor and Graham family houses in Chapman and Bonner Springs), 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - Unidentified, Archival Resource Key
      - Buildings, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - Landscape, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - Oversized Photographs of Places scanned with Box 8, Folder 64, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1946-1984; 9.5; Archival Resource Key
    Miscellaneous subjects include exhibition installations and photographs of Poor's notes on glazes. The Kentucky farm scenes may have been used as research material for a mural commissioned by the Louisville Courier-Journal.
    - Exhibition Installations, Archival Resource Key
      - Carnegie Institute, Frank K. M. Rehn Galleries, and Unidentified Location, 1946-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 65)
      - National Academy of Design, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Kentucky Farm Scenes, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Notes on Glazes by Henry Varnum Poor, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - Nude Models, circa 1908; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Negatives, Slides, and Transparencies, circa 1938-1975; 9.6; Archival Resource Key
    Negatives, slides, and transparencies are of architectural work and artwork by Poor, people, places and miscellaneous subjects.
    - Negatives, Architectural Work, Archival Resource Key
      - Varnum Poor House (exterior), circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 70)
      - Henry Varnum Poor Studio [new] (exterior), 1957 or later; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 71)
      - Unidentified Exteriors, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 72)
      - Unidentified Interiors, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - Negatives, artwork by Henry Varnum Poor, Archival Resource Key
      - Paintings, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 74)
      - Tiles, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 75)
      - Miscellaneous Subjects (Fireplace), circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - Negatives, People, Archival Resource Key
      - Henry Varnum Poor; Poor with others including family and Marcel Duchamp, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 77)
      - Family, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Slides, Archival Resource Key
      - Artwork by Henry Varnum Poor, Pottery, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 79)
      - Places, Alaska (various subjects, including people), 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 80)
      - Miscellaneous Subjects, Rockland County Center for the Arts, Retrospective Exhibition, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - Transparencies, Artwork by Henry Varnum Poor, Archival Resource Key
      - Department of the Interior Mural (Henry Varnum Poor and Anne Poor at work), circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 82)
      - Pottery, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 83)